Zhijian Wen

Curriculum Vitae

Personal Summary

I am a graduate with Master major in Statistics, with experiences in data analysis/modeling, programming including developing R-package and data mining. I am interested in programming and I am enjoying to "talk" with computers. I am keen to join your company where I want to utilize my skills in creative.

Education

2016–2017 Msc - Statistics, University of Auckland.

Key course: Multivariate Analysis, Data Science Practice, Statistical Inference

2015–2016 BSc(Hons) - Statistics, University of Auckland.

Key course: Bayesian Inference, Statistical Computing, Statistical Modelling class representation of **Stats 779**

2012–2015 BSc - Mathematics and Statistics, University of Auckland.

Key course: Data Technologies, Applied Multivariate Analysis

Projects

Master Emulate the persp plot and filled.contour plot in gridGraphics.

The persp() is used for drawing 3-D surface and the filled.contour() is used for drawing filled level contour plot in the **graphics**-package, which is the based package in **R**. My job is to convert (redraw) these two kinds of plots (functions) to **grid**. Supervisor: Associate Professor Paul Murrell

Honours Bayesian inference on forensic glass evidence.

The aim of this project is to fit a zero inflated Poisson mixture model and zero inflated negative mixture model to different situations (e.g. The breaker's distance from the window, Proportion of high persistence fragments).

Supervisor: Professor James Curran

Work Experience

2016-Present Teaching assistant, University of Auckland.

Tutor of Stats 210: It that introduces the theory that underlies the statistical methods used in practical statistics courses. My job is to help students to understand the course concepts during the tutorials and workshops.

Tutor and Marker of Stats 220: This course introduces a variety of computer technologies relevant to storing, managing, and processing data. My job is to help students to understand and solve the questions about the coding. Such as HTML/CSS, SQL and R

Marker of Stats 380: A course of statistical computing using the R statistical computing environment

2015-2016 Summer Scholarship, University of Auckland.

Working on the iNZightMaps-package, used in the mapping module for **iNZight** I am one of the author of the iNZightMaps-package. I was working on the functions for plotting the geographical data and also made it handle coordinate and country data.

Award

2017 Master of Science Honours with First Class Honours

Skills

Advance: R, HTML, LATEX

Fair: SAS, SQL, jags, Linux, Lua, JavaScript

Basic: C, C++, JAON, XML, MATLAB, Excel

Languages

English, Mandarin, Cantonese

Interest

o Game Computing

Statistical Computing

o Table tennis

Physics